#### Career Summary

Jose is a professional with more than 6 years of experience in IT projects. He has more than 2 years of experience building and leading technical teams, with very good communication and applying agile methodologies. He has experience with communication tools, documentation platforms, Scrum, cloud software architecture, CI/CD, automation, databases (SQL and NoSQL), additionally different programming languages. My life motto is "If I don't know, I will learn".

### Summary of Qualifications

#### Proficient In:

- Leadership
- Project Management
- Scrum
- Kanban
- Node.JS
- Express.JS

- Sockets
- SQL and NoSQL
- Redis
- Microservices
- Google Cloud Functions
- Google Cloud
  - Run
- Google Cloud Build
- Cron Jobs
- Automation
- Docker

# Languages

• Spanish (native)

• English (intermediate)

### Career History

### **Gingertec, Dominican Republic**

Engineer Lead and Backend Developer

- Technical planning.
- Implementation of good practices and agile methodologies and direction of Scrum ceremonies.
- Definition of the technical task to be carried out in the Sprint.
- Mentoring and pair-programming to team members.
- Programmer in backend team.

Tools/Technologies: Scrum, ClickUp, AWS EC2, Node.JS, MongoDB

#### **Crops Rent, Pereira, Colombia**

Nov. 2021 – Jul. 2022

Sep. 2022 – Currently

Chief Executive Officer

• Entrepreneurship on hold, where I have managed to build and lead a great team committed to technological development in the agricultural sector.

Tools/Technologies: Scrum, Slack, Arduino, IoT, C++, Node.JS, AdonisJS, Prisma ORM, MQTT

### Adomi Delivery, Cali, Colombia \*

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022

Chief Technology Officer

- Strategic planning to achieve the technical objectives for the platform.
- I did recruitment in the company, interviewing and mentoring those who make up the current Adomi team.

Tools/Technologies: Scrum, Notion, Asana, Slack, Google Cloud Platform

Engineer Lead and Backend Developer

Sep. 2020 – Sep. 2022

- I developed the current cloud architecture of the platform, with a solution based on microservices.
- Managed to reduce cloud costs and increase platform response speed using creative technical

CI/CD

- solutions like a cache with Redis and Serverless services.
- I developed monitoring and alert systems for the platform's technical infrastructure and operations, with Slack bots, automated calls with Twilio, and real-time monitoring of drivers.

Tools/Technologies: Asana, Slack, Google Cloud Platform, Serverless, Microservices, Github, GH Actions, LogDNA, Node.JS, Express.JS, Nest.JS, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, Redis, Pusher, Realtime Location, Docker, Cron Jobs, Firebase Firestore, Push Notifications, Bots, Twilio

## Rappi, Bogotá, Colombia \*

Jul. 2020 – Jan. 2021

Backend Developer

- I was part of the logistics team at Rappi.
- I made endpoints for the Rappitenderos application and asynchronous calls to other microservices with Apache Kafaka.
- I learned about Kotlin, messaging queue, data warehousing, data lakes, and microservices quickly.
- I performed unit tests with Jest on projects in Node, managing to increase code coverage by up to 80%.

Tools/Technologies; Jira, Confluence, Bitbucket, Scrum, Slack, AWS, Kotlin, Spring Boot Framework, Node.JS, Jest, Snowflake, PostgreSQL, Redis, Apache Kafka, LogDNA, Jenkins, Docker

### PortalesCo, Bogotá, Colombia

Nov. 2014 – Jul. 2020

Backend Developer

- I developed several projects for local and foreign companies, such as business directories, sales sites, and inventory management.
- I developed web scraping solutions for a real estate sales platform.

Tools/Technologies: Kanban, Trello, PHP, Laravel, Node.JS, Express.JS, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Python, Web Scraping

#### Education

Universidad Tecnológica de Pereira, Pereira, Colombia

Jan. 2019 – Jul. 2021

Mechatronics Technician

Politécnico San José de Calasanz, La Unión (Valle del Cauca), Colombia Systems and Communications Technician

Jan. 2013 - Dec. 2015